박스 위에 표시하지 않으면
모니카가 화낼꺼야
Oh, you know, Monica is gonna freak
if every box has no label.
아, 맞아
Woo, you're right, yeah
이 상자는
Ok, uhh, "box of...
"쓰레기들"
"crap"
모니카와 챈들러가 돌아오면
애기를 안고 올꺼야. 애기말야
Oh. It's so wild. When Monica and Chandler come back
here, they are gonna have a baby. A baby!
그러게
I know.
잠깐, 로스는 애기가
태어나는 걸 모르잖아
Ah, wait! Ross doesn't know that baby is coming.
전화 걸어줘야
되는거 아냐?
Should we call and tell him?
글쎄, 아마 레이챌이
아직 소리지르고 있을꺼야
I don't know. Rachel is still over there and yelling at him.
나는 그렇게
당하고 싶지 않아
Oh, guy, I would not wanna be humiliated.
- 잠깐 / - 왜?
- Wait. / - What?
- 우리 이래도 되는건가?
- 나도 모르겠어
- Should be we doing this?
- I-I don't know.
이건 좋은 생각이
아닌 것 같아
Oh, quite not a really good idea.
그래, 그런 것 같아
Nop, probably not.
- 그렇다고 그만둔적도 없잖아.
- 그런적 없지!
- But, we've never stopped this before.
- No, sir!
FㆍRㆍIㆍEㆍNㆍDㆍS
10x19-20 The Last One
[자막제작]
코리아닷컴 프랜즈동호회 자막팀
[한글번역]
이승훈(chandler7@korea.com)
이상민(airbone@korea.com)
[한글번역]
[편집/테스트]
배종혁(jonghyukbae@hotmail.com)
[자막편집/싱크]
남효주(hyojunet@nate.com)
임의 수정 및 상업적
용도의 사용을 금합니다
자막 피드백은 게시판을 이용해 주세요
(http://club.korea.com/friends)
[uncut 싱크/자막추가]
sopp7738@korea.com
몇 시간 후면
우리가 부모가 된다니
I can't believe, in a couple of hours,
we are gonna be parents.
애기가 이렇게 일찍
나올 줄은 몰랐어
I can't believe
it's three weeks early.
애기가 빠릿빠릿해서
사랑스러워
I love that our baby is prompt.
에리카 병실이
몇호실이지?
Okey. What room did they're say
Erica was in?
음.. 702호실
Uhh.. 702.
여러분, 힘냅시다.
- Come on, let's go.
이 망할것 좀
내 몸에서 꺼내줘요
Ahhh! Get this damn thing out of me!!!
이건 당신 거예요
Well. These are for you.
저 여자가 낳는 애기
머리 크기 봤어?
Did you see the size of the thing
that was coming out of that woman?
누가 누구를 낳는건지 모르겠어
I couldn't tell who was giving birth to whom.
- 안녕 / - 안녕
- Hi. / - Hey.
좀 어때요?
How is it going?
괜찮아요. 의사가 곧 온대요
It's ok. The doctor said
it'll just still be a while.
기분은 어때요?
How's your feeling?
가끔 아프지만, 아직은
그리 나쁘지 않아요
Well. It hurts sometimes.
It's not too bad yet though.
그래도 약간 무섭네요
It's a little scary.
괜찮을꺼예요
Oh. Honey. You're gonna be fine
첫돌 지난 애를 낳고 있는
702호실 그여자는 어때?
How about the lady in 702
with a toddler coming out of her?
셔츠를 입고 있는 것 같더라니까
I think that kid is wearing a shirt.
당신은 괜찮을꺼예요
You're gonna be fine though.
안녕
Hey.
다시 자
Shh.. Go back to sleep.
나는 집에 가야 돼
I have to go home.
정말 환상적이었어
Oh. This was amazing.
맞아, 진짜 그랬어
It really was.
새로운 기술이 생겼던데?
You've learned some new moves!
같이 일하는 사람 중 한명이
Yeah, well, this guy
at work gave me
장난으로 "미숙련자를 위한
성행위 지도서" 를 줬는데
"Sex for Dummies" as a joke.
끝에 가서 누구에게 이로운지
최후의 승자가 누군지 보라고
Ah. Who's laughing now?
I know!
숨 쉬고, 숨 쉬고
Breathe, breathe,
숨 쉬고 ...
breathe...
잘했어요
Good.
다음 번에는 내가 구령 붙여도 돼?
Next time, can I say breathe?
안돼, 지난 번에 자기가
드라큘라처럼 해서 에리카 겁줬잖아
No, last time you said it like Dracula,
and it scared her!
뭐 필요한 것 있어요?
얼음 조각 좀 갖다 줄까요?
Can I get you anything?
You want some more ice chips?
- 아니요, 괜찮아요
- 잠시만요, 금방 다시 올게요
- No, I'm okay.
- Alright, I'll be right back.
어디 가는 거야?
Where are you going?
화장실 가는데
To use the bathroom.
우리 둘만 남겨놓고 가면 안돼!
You can't leave me alone with her.
- 뭐라고? / - 이 상황은
-What? / -This is exactly the kind of social situation
내가 불편해 하는
사회적 관계 중에 하나잖아
that I am not comfortable with!
사회적 관계 중에서 자기가
편하게 다룰 수 있는 것이 어디 있어?
What kind of social situation
are you comfortable with?
에리카와 단 둘이서 시간을
보내본 적이 없어서 그런단 말야
It's just that we've never spent any time,
you know, alone together.
잘 할거야
You'll be fine.
... 는 물론 아니겠지만
2분 밖에 안 걸릴 거야
Nah, you won't,
but I'll be back in two minutes./Okay.
그래서 ...
So, ah...
여름 휴가 계획 있어요?
Any plans for the summer?
글쎄요, 아마 교회 수련회 정도
I don't know. Maybe church-camp?
그러면 그곳에서
이 얘기는 않하는 게 좋겠네요
Hah. May not wanna mention this.
한 번 생각해 본 적 있어요?
So, you ever wonder which is worse, you know,
출산과 가랑이 사이를 걷어차이는
것 중에서 어느 것이 더 고통스러울지?
going through labor or getting kicked in the nuts?
- 뭐라고요?
- 흥미롭잖아요
- What?
- Well, it's just interesting.
두가지를 동시에 경험하는
사람은 없으니까 아무도 모를테고요
You know, because no one will ever know,
because no one can experience both.
인생에서 규명할 수
없는 위대한 질문 중 하나!
One of life's great, unanswerable questions.
누가 알아요, 그 두 가지보다
더 고통스러운 것이 있을지
I mean, who knows?
Maybe there's something even more painful than those things?
지금 이 상황처럼 말예요
Like this.
- 좋은 아침이야 / - 안녕!
- Morning. / - Hey!
- 그게 뭐야?
- 모니카와 챈들러 집들이 선물이야
- What's that?
- It's my house-warming present for Monica and Chandler.
병아리와 오리 새끼네!
It's a baby chick and duck!
내가 병아리 2세와
오리 2세라고 이름지었어
Uh-huh. And I named them
Chick Jr. and Duck Jr.
기상천외한 이름이네!
I did not see that coming.
새 집에는 넓은
뒷마당도 있으니까 좋을거야
Yeah, I figure they'll love it at the new house, you know?
It has that big backyard.
그리고 늙으면
챈들러가 원래 닭과
And then, when they get old,
they can go to that special farm
오리를 데려간
특별한 농장으로 갈 수 있고
that Chandler took the other chick and duck to.
맞아
Yes.
안타깝게도 그 곳에는
방문이 금지되어 있고
Yeah. It's a shame
people can't visit there.
하지만 그게 규칙인데 어떡해
That is the rule, though.
새로운 소식이 있어!
Guess what?
너 조금 있으면 삼촌이 돼
You're almost an uncle!
- 진짜?
- 에리카가 어제 진통을 겪었고
- What?
- Yeah, Erica went into labor last night.
- 모니카와 챈들러랑
지금 병원에 있어 / -세상에
- Monica and Chandler are
at the hospital right now! / -Oh my God!
그리고 내 예감으로는
분명히 여자 아이일거야
Yeah, and I have a definite feeling
it's gonna be a girl.
피비, 너는 벤 태어날때도
확실히 여자애일 거라고 했잖아
Phoebe, you were sure
Ben was gonna be a girl.
어떤 남자애가 공을
그정도 밖에 못 던진대?
Have you seen him throw a ball?
레이첼 집에 있어?
Is Rachel here?
아직 자는 것 같아
Uh, I think she's still asleep.
아, 맞다!
Hey, hey,
어젯밤에 어떻게 됐어?
레이첼이 상당히 지쳐 보이던데
how did it go with you guys last night?
She seemed pretty pissed at you.
우리는 ...
Uh, we, y'know,
일을 잘 처리했어
we worked things out.
그 미소는 뭐야?
What's that smile?
너희 둘 관계에
무슨 발전이 있었어?
Did something happen with you two?
야, 난 비밀을
누설하는 사람이 아냐
Hey, I'm not one to kiss and tell,
그렇다고 섹스했는데
입다물고 있을 리도 없지
but I'm also not one to have sex and shut up.
우리 어젯밤에 같이 잤다!
We totally did it!
세상에, 너하고 레이첼이랑?
Oh my God. You and Rachel?
나도 알아
정말 엄청난 일이야
I know,
it's pretty great.
그럼 둘이 다시 사귀는 거야?
So what does that mean?
Are you guys getting back together?
나도 몰라
Oh, I.. I don't know.
- 대화는 안 했거든
- 너는 레이첼과 다시 사귀고 싶고?
- We didn't really get to talk.
- But do you wanna get back together?
몰라
I don't know.
정말 엄청났어
It was incredible.
내가 맞게 행동하고 있는 것 같았어
I mean, it just felt so right.
내가 레이첼을 안고 있었을 때
When I was holding her,
절대 놓아주고 싶지 않았어
I mean, I never wanted to let her go.
그래, 레이첼이랑 다시 사귀고 싶어
You know what? Yeah, I do. I wanna be together.
잘됐네!!
YAY!
- 조용히 좀 해!
- '잘됐다'
- Shhh!
- Yay!
레이첼이 파리로
가기는 하는 거야?
So, so is she still going to Paris?
몰라, 그건 아직 생각 안 해봤어
안 갔으면 좋겠는데 ...
Wow, I hadn't thought of that.
I hope not.
오늘은 세상 최고의 날이야
Oh, this is like the best day ever. Ever!
너네 둘이 다시 합칠지 모르고
You guys might get back together,
모니카와 챈들러에게는
아이가 생기고
Monica and Chandler are getting their baby,
오리와 병아리가
다시 이 세상에 등장하고
there are chicks and ducks in the world again!
꼭 내가 뮤지컬
속의 사람인 것 같아
Oh, I feel like I'm in a musical!
♬ 해가 밝게 눈부시게 뜰 때 ♬
♬Daa - raa... When the sun comes up, bright and beaming!
- 그리고 달이
- 좋은 아침이야!
- And the moon comes...♬
- Morning!
쟤 때문에 너네는 노래가
어떻게 끝나는지 평생 모를거야
Guess we'll never know how it ends./Okay.
안녕
Hey.
- 안녕 / -잘 잤어?
- Hey.
- Hey. How did you sleep?
응, 너는?
Good. You?
- 나도
- 너무 잘 잤겠지
- Good.
- I bet you did!
잠깐만, 우리 둘이 있게 해 줄래?
Uh. Would you guys mind giving us a minute?
물론이지, 대신
병아리와 오리 좀 봐줘
Sure, yeah.
Will you just keep an eye
on the chick and the duck?
병아리와 오리라고?
Chick and the duck?
- 내가 알기로는 걔네 죽었 ...
- 죽었다
- Didn't they die...
- Dive.
깨어나도 모를 정도로
농장의 재미에 푹 빠졌어
Yeah, they dove head-first
into fun on the farm.
좋은 아침
So...Morning.
너도
You too.
- 어젯밤은 너무 좋았어
- 나도야, 정말 그랬어
- Last night was just wonderful.
- It really was.
여태까지 살면서 가장 큰 미소를
지으며 일어난 것이 오늘 아침인 것 같아
I woke up today with
the biggest smile on my face.
나도 마찬가지야
I know, me too.
절대 안 일어날 것이라고
생각한 일이었는데
It was... You know,
it was like one of those things
you think is never gonna happen,
실제로 일어나고 보니
and then it does,
그 일은 내가 바래왔던 모든 것이었어
and it's everything you want it to be.
나도 알아
Uh-huh. I know.
정말 ...
It was just,
작별인사하는
최고의 방법이었던 것 같아
it was just the perfect way
to say goodbye.
조금만 더 힘을 줘요
It's just a little bit more, honey.
아파요, 도와 줘요!
Help me! This hurts!
- 그렇게 아파요? / - 네
- Is it really that bad? / - Uh-huh!
당신 가랑이 사이를
걷어 차고, 어떤 게
I think it's time
to kick you in the nuts
더 고통스러운지
비교해볼 때가 된 것 같아요
and see which is worse!
아이 머리가 보입니다
The baby's head is crowning.
세상에
Oh! Oh my God!
내가 지금껏 본 아기
머리 중에 가장 아름다워요
That is the most beautiful
top of a head I have ever seen!
자기도 이리 와서 봐야돼
Chandler, you have to see this!
나는 안봐도 괜찮아
I'm okay.
챈들러, 지금 놓치면 후회할 걸
Chandler, you don't wanna miss this.
우리 아이의 탄생이고
생명 탄생의 기적이야
This is the birth of your child!
It's the miracle of life!
알겠어
Alright.
정말 지저분한 기적인데
Wow, that is one
disgusting miracle.
힘 주기 시작하세요
Start pushing.
어깨가 나옵니다
Here we go.
Here come the shoulders...
남자 아이야
It's a... It's a boy!
/Wow!
아이는 괜찮아요?
Is he okay?
아이는 괜찮습니다
He's just fine.
해냈어요
Oh, you did it!
아기야
It's a baby!
작고 아름다운 아기
A beautiful little baby!
그리고 지저분한 물질도 묻어 있어
And some other stuff I'm gonna
나는 안 묻어있는 것처럼 행동하겠지만
pretend I don't see.
탯줄을 직접 자르시겠습니까?
Would you like to cut the umbilical cord?
되게 말랑말랑한데?
Well, that's spongy.
잘생긴 아기야
Oh, hey handsome!
내가 너를 매우
많이 사랑하며 키워서
Oh, I'm gonna love you so much
that no woman is
어떤 여자에게 너를
견주어도 네가 아깝게 만들 거야
ever gonna be good enough for you!
- 우리는 정말 행운을 타고 났어
- 그러게 말이야
- Oh, we are so lucky!
- I know.
아기가 자기 눈을 닮았네
He has your eyes.
불가능하다는 건 알지만
I mean,
I know that's not possible,
정말 닮았어
but he does.
조금 닦아 올게요
We'll just get him
cleaned up a bit. /Okay.
오, 정말 아름다운 아기예요
Oh my God, he's beautiful.
정말 고마워요
Thank you so much.
당신들이 행복해서 정말 잘됐어요
I'm really happy for you guys.
기분이 어때요?
How do you feel?
지쳐요
I'm tired!
안심하고 있을
시간이 길지 않습니다
Well, you don't have
that much time to relax.
이제 잠시 후면
또 하나의 아기가 나올테니까요
The other one will be along
in a minute.
잠시만요, 누가 언제 나온다고요?
I... I'm sorry,
who should be along
in a what now?
다음 아기가 잠시 후에 나온다고요
The next baby
should be along in a minute.
우리는 한 명의
아기만 주문했는데요
We only ordered one!
쌍둥이라는 걸 모르셨습니까?
You know it's twins, right?
아, 예
Oh, yeah!
알고 있는 사람 두명이
잘도 이런 표정 짓겠습니다?
These are the faces
of two people in the know!
쌍둥이인지 몰랐다는
사실을 믿을 수가 없군요
I can't believe
you didn't know it's twins!
- 이런 적이 한번도 없었거든요
- 세상에
- This has never happened before.
- Well, gosh.
그런 얘기를 들으니까 퍽도 기분이
That makes me feel so special
좋아지고 특별대우를 받는 것 같네요
and good.
잠깐만요, 쌍둥이인지 아셨어요?
Wait, did you know it was twins?
네, 오하이오 주의 병원에서
받은 서류에 그렇게 적혀 있는데요
Yeah, it's here in the paperwork
we got from the clinic in Ohio.
- 누군가 말해주던가요?
- 아닌 것 같은데요
- Anybody tell you?
- I don't think so.
물론 심장박동이 2개 잡힌다고는 했는데
Although, they did mention
something about two heartbeats.
저는 제 심장과
아이의 심장 박동인줄 알았어요
But I thought that was
just mine and the baby's.
2개의 박동이 모두 뚜렷하다고도 했는데
They kept saying
both heartbeats are really strong,
출산을 할 저의 심장 박동이
뚜렷한 것은 좋은 신호라고만 생각했어요
and I thought well, that's good
'cause I'm having a baby.
믿을 수가 없네요
This is unbelievable.
사실 저희 집안에는
쌍둥이 형질이 유전되요
Twins actually run in my family.
그래요? 흥미롭군요
Interesting!
잠깐 이야기할 수 있을까?
Can I see you for a second?
이제 우리는 어떻게 해?
What do we do?
- 어떻게 하냐니, 무슨 소리야?
- 쌍둥이라잖아
- What do you mean "what do we do"?
- Twins!
쌍둥이!
Twins!!
챈들러, 왜 당황하고 그래?
Chandler, you're panicking!
같이 당황하지 않을거야?
Uh-huh! Join me, won't you?!
하나만 우리만 키우고
나머지 하나는 다른 집에 입양시키자
Okay, what do you say we
keep one, and then just like
have an option on the other one?
- 둘을 갈라 놓으면 안 되지
- 왜 안되는데?
- We can't split them up!
- Why not?
아이에게 각각
메달 반쪽씩을 징표로 주고
We could give each of them
half a medallion,
나중에 커서
서로의 위치를 파악하고
and then years later,
they'll find each other
다시 만나면 되잖아!
and be reunited.
모두에게 즐겁고
뜻깊은 하루가 될 텐데
I mean,
that's a great day for everybody.
만약에, 아이를 입양시킨
집이 끔찍한 곳이면?
Okay, what if the person
who adopts the other one
is horrible?
그럴 가능성는 없어
What if they're not?
만약에 왕이 입양하면?
What if it's adopted by a king?
잘도 그러겠네, 내가 듣기로는
왕이 입양할 생각이 있다는 말도 있던데
Yeah, because I hear
the king is looking to adopt.
모니카, 우리는 2명의
아이를 키울 준비는 안 되어 있어
Monica, we are not ready
to have two babies!
상관 없어!
That doesn't matter!
우리는 아이를 위해
정말 오래 기다려 왔어
We have waited so long for this.
나에게는 2명이라도 상관이 없어
I don't care if it's two babies.
3명이라도 상관이 없어
I don't care if it's three babies!
"여덟명이 좋아(Eight Is Enough)"의 전체 주인공이
다 나와도 나는 상관이 없어
I don't care
if the entire cast of
"Eight is Enough"
comes out of there!
우리의 아이이기 때문에
집에 데려가서 기를 거야
We are taking them home,
because they are our children!
그래
Okay. Shhh...
- 맞아 / - 맞고 말고!
- Okay. / - Okay!
그래
Okay!
여기 이 쪽에
준비가 다 된 것 같은데요
It looks like
we're about ready over here.
자, 에리카
다시 힘을 주세요
Come on, Erica,
start pushing again now. /Ow!
여자 아이가 나옵니다
Here she comes!
여자 아이에요?
She? It's a girl?
네
Yeah.
그럼 우리는 남자 여자
하나씩 있게 되는 거네!
Well, now we have one of each!
그리고 둘이면 충분해요
And that's enough!
그리고 나서 작별인사를 하는
최고의 방법이라고 레이첼이 말했어
And then she said it was
the perfect way to say goodbye.
세상에
Oh my God!
- 그래서 뭐라고 말했어?
- 아무 말도 안 했어
- What did you say?
- Nothing!
그 말에 대고 뭐라고 해?
What do you say to that?
로스, 너는 네 감정을
레이첼에게 말해야 해
Ross, you've got to
tell her how you feel!
그럴 수 없어
No way!
그냥 포기할 수는 없는 일이잖아
You can't just give up!
이러한 상황에서
공룡이 그냥 포기했겠어?
Is that
what a dinosaur would do?
- 뭐? / - 난 그냥 네 사고방식이
작용할 만한 방식으로 생각하려는 거야
- What? / - Dude, I'm just trying
to speak your language.
로스, 네가 다시 사귀고
싶어한다는 걸 레이첼은 모르잖아
Ross, Rachel doesn't know
that you wanna get back together.
네 생각을 레이첼이 알게 되면
파리에 가는 걸 다시 생각할 거고
If she did,
she might feel differently.
그럼 가지 않을 수도 있잖아
She might not even go.
정말 그렇게 생각해?
You really think so?
정말이라니까
I'm telling you!
뮤지컬이라면 이 부분이 확실하게
설득하는 노래가 나오는 부분이야
Oh, okay! This is the part
of the musical where there'd be
a really good convincing
song. "Bam-bam-bam,
안 된다는 대답은 받아들이지 마
don't take no for
an answer. Bam-bam-bam,
사랑이 날아가버리게 놔두지 마
don't let love fly away.
Bam-bam-bam-bam..."
- 안녕 / - 노래할 수 있는
여건을 정말 안 만들어 주네
- Hi! / - Can't a girl finish
a song around here?
- 안녕 / -안녕, 내가 방금
에마를 우리 엄마 집에 맡기고 왔어
- Hi! / -So I just dropped
Emma off at my mom's. / -Okay.
에마랑 같이
파리로 가는 것이 아니야?
Oh, you're not taking her
with you tonight?
우선 내가 먼저 가서
좀 자리를 잡고 난 다음에
No, we decided that
I would go ahead and set up first,
우리 엄마가 일요일에 에마를
데리고 파리로 오기로 결정했어
and then my mom would
bring Emma to Paris on Sunday.
우와, 1살된 아기와
8시간이나 비행해야 한다고?
Wow, eight hour flight
with a one-year old?
너희 엄마 힘드시겠는데?
Good luck, mom.
장난해? 내내 황제다이어트 이야기만
Are you kidding?
Eight hours with my mother talking
하는 우리 엄마와 8시간
비행하는 에마가 불쌍하지
about Atkins?
Good luck, Emma!
너네 말이 맞아
최소한 내 마음은 이야기해야 돼
Alright, you know what?
You're right. I should
at least tell her how I feel.
로스, 잠깐만!
Ross, wait!
왜? 왜?
What? What?
나 머핀 하나만 갖다 주라
Could you get me a muffin?
레이첼?
Rachel?
응?
Yeah?
네가 오늘 밤에 떠나는거 알아
I... I know you're leaving tonight,
그래도 말은 해야 할 것 같아서 ...
but I just have to tell you.
너를 사랑해
I love you.
그게 네 계획을 바꿀 지 몰라도
I... I don't know
if that changes your plans at all,
네가 알아야 할 것 같아서
but I thought you should know.
건터
Gunther...
나도 너를 사랑해
Oh... I love you too.
물론 너의 사랑과 의미가 다르지만
Probably not in the same way,
그래도 너를 사랑해
but I do.
내가 까페에서 커피를 마시거나
And, and when I'm in a cafe,
having coffee,
머리가 해보다
더 빛나는 사람을 보면
or I see a man with hair
brighter than the sun,
너를 생각할게
I'll think of you. Aw.
- 안녕, 얘들아 / - 안녕
- Oh... Bye guys. / - Bye.
세상에!
Oh my God!
믿을 수가 없네
Unbelievable!
- 어떻게 하면 좀 나아질 지 알려줄까?
- 너한테 머핀 가져다 주지 않을거야!
- Hey, you know what might help?
- I'm not getting you a muffin!
둘이 같은 자궁 안에 있어서
서로를 알아볼 수 있을 것 같아?
Do you think they recognize
each other from in there?
아마도
Maybe.
서로 다른 아파트에서 분리되어 살다가
Unless they're like two people
who have lived in apartments next to
each other for years,
어느 날 자궁 밖으로 밀려나와서
처음으로 만난 사람들의 경우가 아니라면
and then one day they're pushed through
a vagina and they meet.
이제 에리카를
회복실로 데려갈꺼예요
We're going to take Erica to recovery now.
하고 싶은 말이 있어요
There's something
that we wanna tell you.
여자 아이를
에리카라고 부르기로 했어요
We decided to name
the girl-baby Erica.
세상에, 내 이름과 똑같네요!
Oh my God,
that's just like my name!
세상에나, 정말 그렇네요!
Son of a gun, it is!
어쨌든, 저는 가서
휴식을 취해야 겠네요
Anyway, I'm gonna go
and get some rest.
당신들을 골라서 저는 기뻐요
I'm really glad I picked you guys.
좋은 부모가 될 수 있을거에요
You're gonna make great parents.
챈들러조차도
Even Chandler.
- 잘 가요!
- 잘 가요, 전화할게요!
- Okay, well, bye! / - Bye!
- Bye! We'll call you!
교회 수련회 재미있게 보내세요!
Have fun at church-camp!
- 이 작은 손가락 좀 봐
- 그러게 말이야
- Oh, look at these little bunnies!
- I know!
바꿔도 돼?
You ready to trade?
- 그래 / - 그래
- Okay. / - Okay.
잠깐만 ...
Alright, let's see..
- 나중에 바꿔도 될 것 같은데
- 나도 나중이라도 괜찮아
- We could trade later.
- Yeah, I'm good.
뭘 만들고 있어?
Hey, what are you working on?
아이가 집에 처음으로
오는 것을 환영하는 카드를 만들고 있어
It's a... It's a "welcome
home" sign for the baby.
[환영합니다 - 아기에게 ]
자상해라, 저게 아기야?
["Welcome Home Baby."]
How sweet! Oh, is that the baby?
아니, 내가 페인트에
모르고 앉은 자국이야
No, I sat in the paint.
- 안녕 / - 안녕
- Hey. / - Hey.
- 레이첼과 이야기해 봤어?
- 아니, 이야기 안 할 거야
- So, did you talk to Rachel?
- No, and I'm not going to.
- 뭐 / - 왜 안 할 건데?
- 그냥 레이첼이 거절할 것 같아서 그래
- What? / - Why not?
- Because she's just going to
shoot me down.
아까 건터가 어떻게 됐는지 봤잖아
별로 좋아 보이지는 않아
You guys saw what happened with Gunther.
That did not look like fun.
어떻게 너 자신을
건터에 비유할 수 있어?
How can you compare
yourself to Gunther?
물론, 겉으로 보기에는 건터가
너보다 더 섹시해 보이기는 하지만
I mean, sure,
he's sexy in a more obvious way.
너는 레이첼과 더 깊은 관계가 있잖아
You have a relationship with her,
어젯밤에도 같이 잤고
you slept together last night.
그러고도 레이첼은 가고 싶어 하잖아
Yeah, and she still wants to go!
생각이 어떤지는 아주 명백해
It's pretty clear where she is.
나도 그 심정 이해해, 가끔 나도 ...
Yeah, I know what you mean.
I mean, sometimes...
- 조이 / - 젠장!
- Uh, Joe? / - Damn it!
레이첼에게 말한다고 해도
꼭 지금 해야하는 것은 아니야
Look, even if I were gonna tell
her, I don't have to do it now. Okay?
다시 만나게 될 거고
시간은 얼마든지 있잖아
I'll be seeing her again.
We've got time.
너한테 시간은 없어
레이첼이 파리로 가잖아
No, you don't!
She's going to Paris!
레이첼은 다른 사람을 만날 거야
파리에 얼마나 섹시한 남자가 많은지 알어?
She is going to meet somebody.
Do you know how many hot guys
there are in Paris?
건터같이 매력적인
사람들로만 모인 도시야
It's... It's a city of Gunthers!
- 안녕 / - 안녕
- Hey! / - Hey!
왜 왔어?
What do you have there?
아, 내가 뭘 만들었거든
Oh, I made a little something.
시간이 더 있었으면
더 잘할 수 있을텐데
If I had more time to work on it,
it'd be better, but..
[세상에 나온 것을 축하합니다 - 아기에게]
["Welcome to the World,
Baby Bing."]
세상에, 직접 만든 거야?
Oh my God!
You did that yourself?
자기야, 정말 아름다운데?
Honey, that's gorgeous!
어차피 아기는 글을 못 읽어요, 마이크
You know,
the baby can't read, Mike!
안녕, 택배회사에서
금방 집에 도착했어
Hi! You guys,
the car-service just got here.
모니카와 챈들러는
아직도 집에 안오고
I can't believe
they're not home yet!
나는 아기를 보고 싶은데
비행기 타러 가야 한단 말이야
I have to catch my stupid plane.
I wanna see the baby!
모니카가 금방 택시에서 전화했어
이제 곧 도착 할거야
Monica just called from the cab.
She said they should be here any minute.
그리고 우리가
놀랄만한 일이 있다는데?
And apparently,
there's some big surprise.
맞아, 그 때 모니카 목소리가 밝았어?
Yeah, did she sound
happy about it?
왜냐하면 내 친구 에델의 아기는
작은 수염이 난 채로 태어났거든
'Cause my friend Ethel's baby was
born with a teeny, tiny beard.
안녕
Hey!
세상에! 세상에!
Oh my God! Oh my god!
안녕
Hey! / Hey!
그래, 놀랄만한 일이라는 게 뭐야?
Hey, so what is the big surprise?
병원에서 너희가
2명을 데려온 지 알지?
Okay, okay, awkward question.
The hospital knows
you took two, right?
알아, 쌍둥이거든
Yes, it's twins!
정말 귀엽다
얘네 뭐가 뭐야?
Oh, they're so cute! Now,
what, what kinds are they?
이 것이 남자아이고
저 쪽이 여자아이야
This is a boy, and that's a girl.
여자 아이 이름은 에리카로 정했어
Her name is Erica. /Aw...
얘네 생모도
이름이 에리카였잖아
Hey, that pregnant girl's name was Erica.
맞어, 너네 둘이 같이
시간을 많이 못보낸 것이 안타깝다
Yeah. It's a shame you two didn't
get to spend more time together.
남자 애는 아빠 이름을
따서 잭이라고 지었어
Yeah, we named the boy Jack
after dad.
아빠가 엄청 좋아하겠는데
Aw, he's gonna be so happy.
잭 빙. 이름 정말 맘에 든다
Oh, Jack Bing. I love that.
이름만 들으면 1940년대 신문 같아
Ooh, it sounds like a
'40s newspaper guy, you know?
잭 빙, 아침 뉴스입니다
이 뉴스를 확 열어 제껴야지
"Jack Bing, Morning Gazette.
I'm gonna blow this story wide open!"
정말 예쁘다
Oh my gosh. Wow, so beautiful.
나도 하나 있었으면 좋겠어
I want one.
정말?
Oh yeah?
어느쪽이 더 좋은 지 말해
내가 코트 밑에 싸서 훔쳐가지 뭐
Well, tell me which one,
and I'll try slip it in my coat.
진심으로, 저런 것 하나 만들고 싶어?
Seriously. Wanna make one of those?
그러지 말고 몇명씩 낳지?
One? How about a whole bunch?
- 정말? / - 그래
- Really? / - Yeah!
우리가 노래를 가르치면
본트랩 가족처럼 될 수 있을 것 같아
Ooh, we could teach them to sing,
and we can be like
the Von Trapp family!
나치는 없고 말이야
물론 나치가 없으면 재미가 없겠지만
Only without the Nazis.
Although that sounds kinda dull.
벌써 시간이 다 됐네. 얘들아
지금 나가지 않으면 비행기를 놓칠 것 같아
Oh, you guys, I can't believe this.
But I'll leave now,
or I'm gonna miss my plane.
네가 아기들을 보고
갈 수 있어서 정말 기뻐
I'm just so glad you
got to see the babies.
너희 둘이 아기 둘 동시에 키우기를
시도하는 모습을 보지 못하고 가서 안타깝네
Me too. Oh, I'm just sorry
I'm not gonna be around to watch
you two attempt to handle this!
작별인사를 다시 하는 건
도저히 못할 것 같아
Alright, I can't say goodbye
to you guys again.
나는 너희 모두를 사랑해
I love you all so much.
- 우리도 사랑해 / - 사랑해
- I love you./ - I love you.
- 도착하면 전화해줘
- 그럴게
- Call us when you get there.
- I will.
로스, 이리 와 봐
Ross, come here.
이걸 알아줬으면 좋겠어
I just want you to know..
어젯밤을 ...
Last night..
평생 잊지 못 할거야
I'll never forget it.
나도 잊지 못 할거야
Neither will I.
아, 이제 진짜로 가야 해
Alright, now I really have to go.
그래
Okay.
Au revoir.
(프랑스어로 작별인사)
프랑스 사람들이
진짜로 나를 싫어하겠는데
Oh, they're gonna really hate
me over there.
그래서 그냥 레이첼이
가도록 내버려뒀어?
So, you just let her go?
응
Yeah.
아마 그게 더 나을 수도 있어
Hey, maybe that's for the best.
그래?
Yeah?
그래, 있잖아
Yeah. You know? You just...
레이첼이 어젯밤의 일에 두는
의미 이상을 네가 가지면 안돼
Look, you gotta... You gotta think about
last night the way she does, okay?
아마 ...
Maybe,
같이 자는 게 작별인사하는
최고의 방법이었을지도 몰라
maybe sleeping together was the
perfect way to say goodbye?
쟤네 같이 잤어?
- They slept together?
- I was with you.
난 너랑 있었잖아.
하지만 그러면 레이첼은
너의 마음을 평생 모를거야
But now she'll never know how you feel!
몰라서 괜찮을 수도 있어
Maybe that's okay. You know?
그게 더 나을 방법일 수 있어
Maybe, maybe it is better this way?
이제 너는 새로운 사람을 찾을 수 있어
I mean, now, now you can move on.
너는 레이첼을 잊으려고
오랫동안 노력을 해왔는데
I mean, you've been trying to
for so long,
이제 다른 대륙에 사니까
maybe now that you're on
different continents..
- 맞아? / - 맞아
- Right? / - Right.
이제 정말 잊을 수 있을지도 몰라
Maybe now you can actually do it.
You know?
드디어 레이첼을
완전히 잊을 수 있을거야
You can finally get over her.
맞는 말이야
Yeah, that's true.
하지만 ...
Except ...
나는 레이첼을 잊고 싶지 않아
I don't wanna get over her.
- 뭐라고? / - 잊고 싶지 않아
난 레이첼이랑 같이 있고 싶어
- What? / - I don't!
I wanna be with her.
- 정말? / - 그래
레이첼을 쫓아가서 만나야겠어
- Really?
- Yeah, I'm gonna go after her.
그럼 그래야지!
Yeah, you are! / Woo!
코트 챙겨, 코트 챙겨!
Wait, wait! Get your coat!
Get your coat!
- 내 코트
- 정말 잘 됐다
- My coat...
- This is so cool!
일이 어떻게 되는지
전혀 모르지만, 그래도 신나네
I have no idea what's going on,
but I am excited!
로스, 로스
레이첼이 뭐라고 할 것 같아?
But Ross, Ross. What do you,
what do you think
she's going to say?
나도 모르겠어
I don't know,
레이첼이 날 거절한다고 해도
남은 평생을 후회하지는 않을거 아냐
but I.. Look, even if she shoots
me down, at least I won't spend
the rest of my life wondering
what would have happened.
- 내 코트가 어디 있지?
- 네가 안 입고 왔잖아!
- Where - where is my coat?!
- You didn't bring one!
내 택시가 밑에 있어
내가 공항까지 태워 줄게
My cab's downstairs,
I'll drive you to the airport.
- 행운을 빌어줘
- 서둘러!
- Okay, guys, wish me luck.
- Hurry!
행운을 빌어!
Good luck, good luck!
세상에
Oh my God!
로스는 레이챌 쫓아가고,
너네는 애기들을 데려오고
Ross is going after Rachel,
and you guys got the babies
내 생애 최고의 날이야
this is like the best day ever.
왜 내 쇼파에 엉덩이 모양의
페인트 자국이 있지?
Why is there an ass-shape
paint stain on my couch?
마이크, 당신한테 묻잖아요
Get your question, you, Mike! (??)
제시간에 도착할 수 있을까?
~~ make it in a time?
내가 안전하게 운전해서
면허가 취소된 줄 아니?
~~
if I drived carefully?
안전벨트가 없잖아!
There's no seatbelt!
괜찮아, 사고가 나면
엔진이 터질테니까
That's okay.
If - if we hit anything,
the engine will explode,
차에서 튀어나가는 쪽이 더 좋아
so you know, it's better
if you're thrown from the car.
- 좋아, 가자 / - 그래
- Alright, alright, let's do this!
- Okay!
- 18번가 동쪽 끝으로 가주세요
- 전 손님 안받아요
- Hey! / - 18th and East End.
- I - I don't take passengers.
승차거부는 불법이에요
Hey! The law says you have
to accept any fare.
이해를 못하시나본데요
이건 진짜 택시가 아니에요
No, you don't understand.
This isn't a real cab.
신고하겠어요
등록번호가 뭐죠?
Alright, I gotta report you.
What's your medallion number?
내 등록번호는...
My medallion number is,
당장 내려!
"Get out of the cab!"
- 뭐요?
- 당장 내려, 당장 내리라고!
- What?
- Get out of the CAAAAAB! Get out of the CAAAAB!
얘들아, 잘봐
Hey, you guys...
- 안돼! / - 알았어
- No! / - Okay.
지금 집들이 선물 줘도 될까?
Oh, hey, hey, can I give you guys
your house-warming present now?
- 그럼 괜찮고 말고 / - 좋아
- Now, that you can do. / - Alright!
궁금한게 있어
I have a question.
기저귀 안을 보지 않고
누가 누군지 알 수 있어?
Without looking in there diapers
can you tell them apart?
물론이지, 난 엄마라구
Of course, I can. I'm their mother.
정말? 좋아
Oh, yeah? Okay.
얘가 누구지?
Which one is that one?
얜 잭이야
That's Jack.
잭은 고등학교에서
남자애들한테 인기 많겠는걸
Oh! Jack's gonna have tough
time in high school with ~~
병아리 2세야
Ah... Chick Jr.?
오리 2세야
Duck Jr.?
엄마한테서 숨지 마
Don't hide from mama!
- 이제 눈 떠도 돼
- 다리 벗어났어?
- You can open your eyes now
- Are we off the bridge?
- 응 / - 길 건너던
할머니는 아직 살아있어?
- Yes. / - Is the old woman
on the bicycle still alive?
그래, 뒤로 뛰어서 살았어
Yes, she jumped right back up.
세상에, 피비
좀 천천히 가
Oh my God, Phoebe,
slow down!
- 레이첼을 제시간에 잡고싶긴 한거야?
- 그래, 그래도 택시 안에서 죽기는 싫어
- Do you wanna get to Rachel in time?
- Yes, but I don't wanna die in your cab!
정말 죽여버리기 전에 입 다물어
You should have thought
of that before you got in!
- 톨게이트다 / - 뭐?
- Toll-booth. / - What?
톨게이트라고!
Toll-booth!
동전박스
그 안에 보면 동전들 있을거야
Four bucks. There are quarters
in the glove compartment.
빨리해!
- Hurry! / - Okay!
- Okay.
유리창 한번 더럽게 깨끗하네
Damn, that window is clean.
선물 가지러가서 왜 그렇게
오래걸리나 했는데 이젠 알겠다
We were wondering what was
taking so long with the gift,
but now we understand
이러구 있느라 늦은거구나
you were doing this.
너희들을 놀라게 해주고 싶었는데
Okay, I wanted to surprise you,
내 집들이 선물은
병아리랑 새끼오리야
but for your house-warming gift,
I got you a baby-chick and a baby-duck!
정말? 병아리랑
새끼오리를 준단 말이야?
Really?
You got us a chick and a duck?
좋은데, 아기들이 있는 집에
새들을 선물한다는거지?
Oh, great! Just what you want for
a new house with infants. Bird feces.
근데 테이블에서 뛰어내렸나봐
어디갔는지 찾을 수가 없어
Yeah, yeah, they must have jumped
off the table, 'cause now they're gone!
- 걱정마, 찾으면 되지
- 난 가서 쌍둥이들 좀 볼게
- Oh, don't worry, we'll find them.
- Actually, I'm gonna go check
on the twins.
그래
Alright.
내가 지금 뭘 밟은거야?!
- Oh God! What did I just step on? - Oh!
괜찮아, 그냥 에그롤이야
- It's okay, it's just an egg roll. - Oh..
내 에그롤을 밟은거야?!
You stepped on my egg roll?
미안하다. 중국음식이
바닥에 놓여있으니 조심해야하는데
I'm sorry, I didn't know to look
for Chinese food on the floor.
그거 접시에 담아두고 가
Just put it on a plate and leave.
- 좋아, 이녀석들 찾아보자 / - 그래
- Okay, let's find these birds.
- Alright.
잠깐, 잠깐
Wait, wait.
이거 들려?
Do you hear that?
테이블 안에 들어있어
Oh! They're in the table!
그럼 안되는데
Well, that can't be good!
- 얘네들 꺼내야 하는데
- 어떻게?
- We gotta get them out of there!
- How?
한번 불러보면 어떨까?
너 새들 부르는 방법 알아?
Oh, oh! Maybe we can lure them out.
You know any birdcalls?
그래, 난 숲사람이잖아
Oh, tons, I'm quite the woodsman.
좀 흔들어 보면 나올지도 몰라
Well, maybe we can just tip
the table a little.
조이, 잠깐! 공!
Joey, wait! The ball! / Oh!
어떻게 해야지?
Oh God! So what do we do?
글쎄, 아래쪽을
어떻게 열어볼 수 없을까?
I don't know. Maybe we
can open this up somehow. / Okay.
다 접착제로 붙어있네
No... It's all glued together.
이걸 부숴서 열어야 하는거야?
Does that mean we have to bust it open?
글쎄, 그래야 할지도
I don't know. Maybe.
세상에..
Oh my God!
그러게
I know!
축구 테이블인데..
It's.. It's the foosball table.
있잖아, 어쩔 수 없어
All right, you know what?
We don't have a choice.
내가 맡고싶어하던
그 SF영화 배역하고 같은 상황이야
It's like I would have said in that
sci-fi movie if I'd gotten the part.
이 안에 있는 사람들을 구해내야해
"Those are our men in there,
we have to get them out!
내 삶에 가장 중요한 걸 희생해서라도
Even if I have to sacrifice the
most important thing in my life;
내 타임머신을...
my time-machine."
- 그 영화 제작 되긴 했냐?
- 아니
- Did that movie ever get made?
- It did not.
잭 와인버그씨 부인한테서 전화가 와있습니다
Jack Weinberg, wife calls you.
- 로스? 어디가는거야?
- 레이첼이랑 얘기하러...
- Ross, where are you going?
- To talk to Rachel,
그것 때문에 살인택시를
타고 여기까지 온거 아냐?
isn't that why we took a ride
in the death-cab?
그냥 갈 수 있을거 같아?
공항까지 사람 쫓아와 본적도 없어?
What? What are you just gonna
walk up to her at the gate?
Have you never chased anyone
through the airport before?
내 경찰 드라마가 취소된 뒤로는 해본적 없는데
Not since my cop-show got cancelled.
거길 통과하려면
비행기 티켓이 있어야해
You have to get a ticket
to get past security.
- 뭐? 시간이 부족해 - 그런식으로 하면 당연하지, 서둘러
- What? We're never gonna make it! - Not with that attitude! Now, haul ass!
다들 좀 천천히
움직여주시면 고맙겠습니다
Okay, if you could all walk
slower, that'd be great.
부인, 여권 좀 보여주시겠습니까?
Madame, your passport please?
세상에, 고등학교 때 배운 불어가
하나도 생각안나면 어쩌나 걱정했는데
Oh my God! I was so afraid I wasn't
gonna remember any of my high-school French,
방금 당신이 말한건 한마디도
빼놓지 않고 다 알아들었어요
but I understood every word you just said!
표좀 보여주시겠습니까?
Your boarding pass, please.
있었는데
Oh.
이럴리가 없는데
Oh, shoot. I had it.
Oh, I can't believe this.
- 부인, 표가 없...
- 있어요, 있어 있다고요
- Madame, if you don't have your
boarding pass... - I have it, I have it, I have it.
좋아요, 지금 찾지는 못하겠는데
그래도 32C 좌석이었다는건 기억해요
Oh, okay, I can't find it, but I
remember that I was in seat 32C,
그게 제 가슴 사이즈거든요
because that's my bra-size.
부인, 표를 가지고 있..
Madame, you must have your boarding pass..
알았다고요, 36D 였으면
그냥 들어갈 수 있었을텐데
Okay, fine! But you know what?
If I was in 36D, we would not
be having this problem.
안녕하세요
표를 한장 사려고 하는데요
Hey, I need a ticket.
한장? 내가 여기까지
운전해서 널 데리고 왔는데
Just one?
I drive you all the way down here,
- 어떻게 되는지 못본단 말야?
- 그래, 두장 주세요. 표 두장요
- and I don't get to see how it works out?
- Fine, two tickets, I need two tickets.
신혼여행이에요
We're on our honeymoon.
- 목적지는요? / - 상관없어요
아무데나 제일 싼데로요
- And the destination?/ - I don't care.
Whatever is the cheapest.
너랑 결혼하다니
난 참 운도 좋아
I'm so lucky I married you.
젠장, 어디 갔지?
Oh! Shoot! Damn it! Where is it?
찾았다, 찾았다
Oh! Oh! I found it! I found it!
내가 찾을거라고 했죠?
당신은 다른 사람이네요
Hah! I found it!
I told you I would find it! In your face! You're a different person.
좋아, 421 파리행 비행기
Okay, flight 421 to Paris.
못찾겠는데.. 넌 찾았어?
I don't see it, do you see it?
아니, 우리 놓친거야?
No, did we miss it?
아냐, 아직 떠날 때까지
20분쯤 남았어
No, no, no. That's impossible.
It doesn't leave for another 20 minutes.
비행기 번호를
잘못 알았을 수도 있어
Maybe we have the flight-number
wrong. God.
- 여보세요
- 나야, 로스 바꿔줄게
- Hello.
- Hey, it's me. Here's Ross.
- 뭐? / - 받아
- What? Hey, hey,
- 모니카 / - 쌍둥이들이
내는 귀여운 소리 좀 들어봐
- listen.. / - Oh my God! Ross,
you wouldn't believe the cute little
noises the twins are making. Listen.
모니카
Monica?
- 미안해, 좀전엔 했었는데
- 괜찮아, 저기..
- Oh, I'm sorry. Shoot,
they were doing it before.
- That's alright. Listen, listen.
잠깐잠깐, 또 한다
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
Here they go again.
- 귀엽지 않아?
- 정말 예쁘다
- Isn't that cute?
- That is precious!
잘 들어
Listen!
레이첼이 탄 비행기 정보가 필요해
-I need Rachel's flight information. -Oh, okay.
421번 비행기
8:40분 출발
Alright, it's flight 421.
Leaves at 8:40.
나도 그렇게 알고 있는데
여기 안나와있어
Yes, that's what I have.
It's not on the board.
여기엔 421번 비행기
8:40분, 뉴아크 공항 출발
That's what it says here. Flight
421, leaves at 8:40, Newark airport.
- 뭐라고? / - 뉴아크 공항
- What? / - Newark airport.
왜? 어딘데?
Why, where are you?
JFK 공항
JFK.
걱정마, 얘들아
우리가 꺼내줄게
Don't worry, you guys, we're
gonna get you out of there.
그리고 작은 새용 보청기도 사줄게
And we're also gonna buy you
tiny, bird hearing-aids.
좋아, 시작한다
Okay. Here goes.
왜 그래?
What's the matter?
우선 테이블에
작별인사를 해야겠어
I need to say goodbye to the table first.
이해해
I understand.
그래
Okay.
테이블아!
Table,
우리가 정말 좋은
시간들을 보내게 해줬어
you have given us so many great times.
그리고 너희들
And you guys,
조던, 빅터
Jordan, Victor,
조엘 ...
Joel...
너희들 전부 ...
All of you guys...What can I say?
너희들은 우릴 ...
You guys make us
멋지게 만들어줬어
look good.
- 뭐 할 말 있어?
- 모르겠어
- You wanna say anything?
- I don't know.
그냥
Except that,
마지막으로 ...
for one last time...
화이팅, 화이팅, 화이팅...
Good game, good game,
good game, good game,
화이팅
good game.
이제 해야지
Okay, here we go.
못하겠어
I can't do it.
나도 못해
Well, I can't do it either.
- 찾았어?
- 응, 테이블 안에 갖혔어
- Hey! Did you find them?
- Yeah, they're stuck inside the table!
그래서 이걸 부숴야 할 거
같은데, 우리 둘다 못하겠어
We have to bust it open, but
neither of us can do it!
그럼 힘들거야
Oh, well sure.
This gotta be so hard.
내가 할게, 줘봐
I'll do it. Gimme!
피비!
Phoebe! Wow! No, no, no!
와, 이렇게 빨리
달려본 적은 없는데
Well, I've never gone this fast before.
피비, 그만 둬
뉴아크 공항까지 한시간은 걸려
Phoebe, forget it, okay? Newark
is - is like an hour away.
- 절대 시간내에 못갈거야
- 핸드폰 가지고 있어, 전화해봐
- There's no way we're gonna make it in time. / - She's got her cell, you could call her.
- 전화로 얘기하진 않을거야
- 선택의 여지가 없어
- I am not doing this over the phone. - You don't have any other choice!
- 여보세요?
- 레이첼! 다행이다
- Hello?
- Rachel? Oh, good.
- 근데 지금 막 비행기 탔어? / - 응
- Hey, by the way, did you just get
on the plane?/ - Yeah.
할만은 했네, 제대로 가기만
했으면 지금 레이첼 잡았을거야
For what it's worth, we would have caught her if we were at the right airport. / Yay.
레이첼, 잠깐 기다려
Uh, Rach, hang on.
피비, 괜찮아?
Phoebe? Is everything okay?
사실 아냐
Uhm, actually no.
지금 너 비행기에서 내려야해
No, you've... You have to
get off the plane.
뭐? 왜?
What? Why?
좋지 않은 기분이 들어
I have this feeling that
something's wrong with it.
왼쪽 필란쥐에 문제가 있는거 같아
Something is wrong with
the left Philange.
비행기엔 이상 없을거야
Oh, honey, I'm sure there's
nothing wrong with the plane.
이제 끊어야해
파리에 도착하는대로 전화할게
Alright, look, I have to go.
I love you, and I will call you
the minute I get to Paris.
무슨 일이죠?
Uhm, what was that?
좀 미친 친군데요, 느낌이 좋지
않다고 비행기에서 내리라네요
Oh, that was just my crazy friend. She told me I should get off the plane, because she had a feeling
왼쪽 필란쥐에 이상이 있다면서요
that there was something wrong with the left Philange.
좋지 않게 들리는데요
Okay, that doesn't sound good.
걱정마요. 항상 이런데
절대 맞추는 일이 없어요
I wouldn't worry about it. She's always coming up with stuff like this, and you know what? She's almost never right.
하지만 가끔은 맞추죠?
But she is sometimes.
뭐...
Well...
- 뭐하는거죠?
- 이 비행기 못타겠어요
- Wait, what are you doing?
- Well, I can't take this plane now.
- 죄송한데, 어디가시는거죠?
- 난 비행기에서 내려야겠어요
- Excuse me, sir, where are you going? / - I have to get off this plane, okay?
이 여자분 친구분이 왼쪽 필란쥐에
문제가 있는거 같은 느낌이 든대요
Her friend has a feeling something's
wrong with the left Philange.
땅콩 좀 가져다 주시겠어요?
Could I get some peanuts?
- 비행기에 문제가 있나요?
- 비행기에는 문제가 없어요
- What's wrong with the plane?
- There's nothing wrong with the plane.
- 왼쪽 필란쥐요
- 필란쥐는 없어요
- Yeah! The left Philange!
- There is no Philange!
세상에, 비행기에 필란쥐가 없대요
Oh my God. This plane doesn't
even have a Philange!
- 나도 내려야겠어요
- 부인, 앉아주세요
- I'm not flying on it!
- Ma'am, please sit down!
- 무슨 일이에요?
- 다들 내리세요
- What's going on?
- We're all getting off.
비행기에 필란쥐가 없대요!
There is no Philange!
말도 안돼
This is ridiculous! I...
그러지, 뭐
Yeah, okay.
좋아, 여기 일은 끝났어
Alright. My job here is done.
대단하네
That was... Impressive.
그러게, 도구는 거의
사용하지도 않았어
Yeah, you didn't even use the
tools for most of it!
쓰니까 자꾸 느려지더라고
Yeah, they were just slowing me down.
아기들 보러 다시 가야겠다
Alright, I have to get back to the babies.
너희 계집애들은 나중에 보자
I'll see you girls later.
테이블이 부서져서 유감이다
Sorry about the table, man.
그래
Yeah.
새로 살거야?
You gonna buy a new one?
아마 안살거 같아
Probably not. Nah.
네가 없으면
별로 하고싶지 않을거 같아
I don't know how much I'm gonna
wanna play after you go.
뭐, 그래도 이녀석들은 구했잖아
- Well, at least we got these
little guys out. / - Yeah.
우리가 얼마나 걱정했는데
Aww, we were worried about you!
이녀석들이 손에 싸놓는데
다시 익숙해져야겠는데
Hm. I guess I better get used to
things crapping in my hand, huh?
이녀석들이 그리울거야
I'm gonna miss these little guys.
새들이 옆에
다시 있으니까 좋더라고
It was nice having birds around again.
저기 말이야
Hey, you know what?
이녀석들 여기서
네가 키우는게 어때?
Maybe we should keep them here with you.
- 뭐? / - 우린 이제 할 일도 많고
- What? / - Yeah, I mean we've got
a lot going on right now.
거기다 여기서 얘네들
자기 방을 가질 수도 있잖아
And, plus, here they'd have their own room.
거위를 키워도 되겠다
I could get a goose!
새판을 만들려고?
You know, I - I think you're
set with the poultry.
고마워
Thanks man.
들었지, 너희들 여기서 살거야
Did you hear that, you guys?
You're gonna get to stay here!
좋은 생각이야
And, and it's good, you know, 'cause,
네가 여기 들릴
이유가 하나 생기니까
'cause now you
have a reason to come visit.
다른 이유도 있을거야
I think there may be
another reason.
그럼..
So,
쑥스럽게 안을까?
awkward hug or
멋지고 쿨하게 악수를 할까?
lame cool guy handshake?
멋지고 쿨한 악수로 하자
Uh, lame cool guy handshake, yeah.
확실히 비행기는 이상 없습니다
Ma'am, I assure you, the plane is fine.
필란쥐는 고쳤나요?
And you fixed the Philange?
네, 필란쥐는 고쳤어요
Yes, the Philange is fixed.
만약의 사태에 대비해서
예비 필란쥐도 실어뒀어요
As a matter of fact, we put a whole lot of extra Philanges onboard, just in case.
- 어딨지? / - 안보여
- Where is she?
- I don't see her.
- 레이첼, 레이첼 그린
- 저다
- Rachel! Rachel Green!
- There she is!
레이첼, 레이첼
Rachel! Rachel!
죄송합니다만
표는 가지고 계신가요?
Wow, excuse me, sir,
do you have a boarding pass?
아뇨, 지금 들어간
사람하고 잠깐 얘기 ...
No, no,
I just have to talk to someone.
죄송하지만 표 없이는
들어가실 수 없습니다
I'm sorry, you cannot go any
further without a boarding pass.
아뇨, 전..
No, no, no, but...
레이첼!
RACHEL!!
너희들 여기서 뭐하는거야?
Oh my God... What..
What are you guys doing here?
이제 네 차례야
Okay, you're on.
왜? 무슨일이야?
무섭잖아, 무슨일이야?
What? What? Ross, you're
scaring me. What's going on?
무슨 일이냐하면...
- Okay, the thing is../ - Yeah?
가지마
Don't go.
뭐?
What?
내 곁에 있어줘
널 너무 사랑해
Please, please stay with me.
I am so in love with you.
제발 가지마
Please, don't go.
세상에
Oh my God.
알아, 진작 말했어야 했는데
I know, I know. I shouldn't have
waited 'till now to say it,
정말 바보 같았어, 미안해
That was stupid, okay? I'm sorry,
진심으로 말하는거야
but I'm telling you now.
사랑해
I love you.
비행기 타지마
Do not get on this plane.
아가씨, 비행기 타실건가요?
Miss? Are you boarding the plane?
네가 날 사랑하는 걸 알아
Hey, hey. I know you love me.
난 알 수 있어
I know you do.
아가씨?
Miss?
- 난 비행기 타야해
- 아냐, 가지마
- I - I have to get on the plane.
- No, you don't.
- 가야돼 / - 가지마
- 나때문에 기다리고 있어, 로스
- Yes, I do. / - No, you don't.
- They're waiting for me, Ross.
지금은 안되겠어, 미안해
I can't do this right now, I'm sorry.
미안해
I'm sorry.
레이첼
Rachel?
정말 미안해
I'm so sorry.
꼭 남아줄거라고 생각했는데
I really thought she'd stay.
안됐다
I'm sorry.
다 됐네
Well, that's it.
다 쌌어
Everything's packed.
기분이 이상해
Wow, this is weird.
그러게
I know.
그럼 먹을거 하나도 없는거야?
Yeah. Uh, does this mean
there's nothing to eat?
네 냉장고 안에
은 라자냐 3개 넣어놨어
I put three lasagnas
in your freezer.
사랑해
I love you!
시간에 맞춰 갔어?
So did you guys make it in time?
그래, 레이첼이랑 얘기했어
Yeah, yeah, he talked to her,
그래도 레이첼 비행기 탔고
but she got on the plane anyway.
로스는 어디갔어?
Where's Ross?
집에 갔어
아무도 보고싶지 않대
He went home.
He didn't want to see anybody.
로스, 나야
Ross, hi. It's me.
나 지금 막 다시 비행기 탔어
I just got back on the plane.
기분이 너무 안좋아
And I just feel awful.
이렇게 우리 사이를
끝내고 싶지 않았는데...
That is so not how I wanted
things to end with us.
그렇게 ...
It's just
그렇게 네가 나타나서
그런 말들을 할줄은 상상도 못했어
that I wasn't expecting to see you,
and all of a sudden you're there
and saying these things...
여기 앉아서 내가
해야했던 말들을 생각했는데...
And... And now I'm just sitting
here and thinking of all the stuff
I should have said, and I didn't.
난 너한테 나도
널 사랑한다는 말조차 못했잖아
I mean, I didn't even get to
tell you that I love you too.
정말 널 사랑하는데...
Because of course I do.
사랑해
I love you.
사랑해..
I love you...
내가 지금 뭘 하고 있는거지?
What am I doing?
사랑해!
I love you!
널 봐야겠어
Oh, I've gotta see you.
- 여기서 내려야겠다
- 세상에
- I've gotta get off this plane.
- Oh my God!
- 잠깐만요
- 부인, 제발
- Excuse me?
- Miss? Please,
앉아주세요
sit down!
정말 죄송한데
전 지금 내려야겠어요
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry, but
I need to get off the plane, okay?
지금 내려서 사랑한다는
말을 전해야 할 사람이 있어요
I need to tell someone
that I love love them.
아가씨, 비행기에서
내리실 수 없습니다
Miss, I can't let you
off the plane.
내리게 놔두란 말야!
Let her off the plane!
다시 자리에 앉아주세요
I am afraid you are gonna
have to take a seat.
- 이해를 못하시나본데요
- 이해를 좀 해보란 말야!
- Oh, please, miss, you don't understand! / - Try to understand!
제가 비행기에서
내릴 수 있는 방법이..
Oh, come on, miss, isn't there any way that you can just let me off...
안돼, 안돼!
No! No!
세상에, 내린거야?
Oh my God. Did she get off the plane?
비행기에서 내린거냐고!
Did she get off the plane?
나 비행기에서 내렸어
I got off the plane.
비행기에서 내렸구나
You got off the plane.
널 정말 사랑해
I do love you.
나도 널 사랑해
다신 널 놓지 않을거야
I love you too, and I'm never
letting you go again.
그래, 나도 그러길 바래
다신 떨어지고 싶지 않아
Okay. 'Cause this is where I
wanna be, okay? No more messing
around. I don't wanna mess this up again.
우리 이제 바보같은 짓은 그만하자
Me neither, okay?
We are - we're done being stupid.
그래
Okay.
- 이제 같이 있는거야, 이렇게...
- 그래, 이렇게
- You and me, alright? This is it.
- This is it.
우리가 잠깐 헤어져 있던게...
Unless we're on a break....
지금 농담할 때가 아니잖아
Don't make jokes now.
좀 조심해서 다뤄주세요
할머니 유품이에요
Okay, please be careful with that.
It was my grandmother's.
조심하세요
Be careful.
그게 트럭에서 떨어진다고 해도
별로 나쁘지 않을거에요
If that falls off the truck,
it wouldn't be the worst thing.
그래
- Wow. / - I know.
참 좁아보인다
It seems smaller somehow.
여기 원래 보라색이었어?
Has it always been purple?
잘 봐둬라
Look around, you guys.
여기가 너희들의 첫 집이었단다
This was your first home.
행복한 곳이었지
And it was a happy place,
사랑과 웃음이 가득했던...
filled with love and laughter..
더 중요한 건
...............?
But more important, because of
rent control, it was a friggin' steal!
그러고 보니까 우리들 전부
여기서 잠깐씩은 살았던거 알아?
Hey, do you realise that at one
time or another we all lived
in this apartment?
정말 그러네
Oh, yeah, that's true.
난 아냐
Uh, I haven't.
여름학기에 할머니하고
살았던 적 있잖아
Wait a minute. What about that
summer during college that
you lived with grandma,
댄서한다고 했었잖아
and you tried to make it as a dancer?
10년동안 그 얘기 안
하고 살았던거 알아?
Do you realise we almost made
it ten years without that coming up?
잊어버릴 뻔했다
Oh, honey, I forgot.
트리거씨한테
열쇠 두고간다고 했는데
I promised Treeger
that we'd leave our keys.
아, 그래
Oh, okay.
이게 끝인거 같네
So, I guess this is it.
그래
Yeah.
그런 것 같다
I guess so.
생각했던 것보다 더 힘들어
This is harder than I thought it would be.
괜찮아
Oh, it's gonna be okay.
바로 새집으로 가야돼?
아니면 시간 좀 있어?
Do you guys have to go to the
new house right away, or do you
have some time?
시간 좀 있어
We got some time.
그럼 커피나 한잔 할까?
Okay, should we get some coffee?
그러자
Sure.
어디서?
Where?